{
    "id": "549bf227746846af8e244707bbdac495",
    "title": "Subject-Verb Agreement",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "He and his wife ……………………….. arrived.",
            "description": "Two or more singular nouns connected by and take a plural verb.",
            "answers": [
                "has",
                "have"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "889fe1e438f7405b80c7edca0df58cde"
        },
        {
            "question": "Oil and water ……………………… not agree.",
            "description": "Two or more singular nouns connected by and take a plural verb.",
            "answers": [
                "do",
                "does"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "bf9c977c89e2424998ff858c64f16c5b"
        },
        {
            "question": "My mentor and benefactor ………………………. no more.",
            "description": "When two singular nouns refer to the same person, we use a singular verb.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "67035e074227477a99c05e4816072c55"
        },
        {
            "question": "The secretary and the chairman ……………………………. present at the meeting.",
            "description": "Here the articles used with the two nouns indicate that they refer to different people and hence we use a plural verb.",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "3f470bd49482436a916572903a046fdf"
        },
        {
            "question": "Each person …………………………. a vote.",
            "description": "We use a singular noun and a singular verb after each.",
            "answers": [
                "has",
                "have"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "0398e679bbeb4c69b82cac02f84d727e"
        },
        {
            "question": "Each day ………………………… its own challenges.",
            "description": "We use a singular noun and a singular verb after each.",
            "answers": [
                "bring",
                "brings"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "e1a5d61597ae4c57bf2c415b59aef4b8"
        },
        {
            "question": "Neither Rahul nor Rohan ………………………… passed the exam.",
            "description": "The verb is singular when two or more singular nouns are connected by nor.",
            "answers": [
                "has",
                "have"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "fd71aa3ccc994ac2b524852c75c1c3de"
        },
        {
            "question": "Either Peter or James ………………………. left his umbrella in the classroom.",
            "description": "The verb is singular when two or more singular nouns are connected by or.",
            "answers": [
                "has",
                "have"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "c6f18636a4b141caa7ab5f0f7aaa81b0"
        },
        {
            "question": "Neither the manager nor his personal assistants ……………………… there.",
            "description": "When the subjects joined by or or nor are of different number, the verb is plural. In this case, put the plural subject close to the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "5d82c9d32a6541a7a8ed9055b2c4f761"
        },
        {
            "question": "Neither he nor I ………………………… responsible for this.",
            "description": "When the subjects connected by or or nor are of different persons, the verb agrees in person with the nearest subject.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are",
                "am"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "650e3dcd4c05433c932c1477ec686453"
        },
        {
            "question": "Neither you nor he ………………………… a good student.",
            "description": "When the subjects connected by or or nor are of different persons, the verb agrees in person with the nearest subject.",
            "answers": [
                "are",
                "is"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "47e6ea6d3aca455f8f6c53c2a436557b"
        },
        {
            "question": "Everyone of them ……………………… there.",
            "description": "We use a singular verb after every and everyone.",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "e18b3c066efd40fc93437165c75d52ef"
        }
    ]
}